$Brandon\ Spann\ |\ {\tt Electrical\ Engineering}$

bmspann1@catamount.wcu.edu | 704-530-1472 |

Summary

Electrical Engineering student with three years of fundamentals and experience. Primarily focusing on more field and work experience. Possess excellent interpersonal abilities and a wide range of technical skills. Enjoy being part of a team, as well as managing, motivating, and joining a productive team, and thrive in high-pressure and challenging working environments.

Core Competencies

Mathematical ModelingCircuit AnalysisCircuit DesignCritical ThinkingProject PlanningSignal ModulationControl SystemsDecision MakingHardware Design and SimulationPower SystemsAnalog and Digital CommunicationProblem Solving

Professional Experience

SJE Rhombus, FL

Electrical Engineer Intern

2020 - 2020

- Worked alongside professional engineers and designers, gaining exposure to project coordination and relevant computerassisted engineering software.
- Performed analysis and design of electrical schematics for new market potential, as well as fabricated and upgraded existing control systems.
- Assisted with tasks that included filing, scanning, data entry, documentation, and Power Point presentation
- Assisted as field trainee with surveying and conducting instrumentation measurement.

BLUM, NC

Manufacturing Engineer Intern

2018 - 2019

- Developed computer aided designs and true view drawings to be processed into a database
- Incorporated the use of laser engraving, 3D modeling, and injection molding to accomplish the goals of various projects during my time at the company.
- Communicated and resolved various issues regarding quality to improve efficiency and customer satisfaction.

Education

Western Carolina University, Cullowhee, NC

2019 - 2024

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Course Highlights - Network Theory II, Logic Systems Design I, Computer Utilization, Ordinary Differential Equations, Engineering Practice & Principles III, Modern Physics, Digital System Design, Calculus III

GPA 3.23

Dortmund University, Dortmund, Germany

2019 - 2019

Western Carolina University – Study Abroad

Skills

Microsoft Project ECAD & CAD SOLIDWORKS MATLAB

MS Office Suites Autodesk Inventor Pro UX & UI Design Verilog & VHDL

Adobe Creative Suites Blender (Rendering and Modeling) Python, CSS, C++, JavaScript

Additional Information

- Cultural Experiences: Visited 3 countries in 2 continents and studied in Germany over a few month
- **Social Impact:** National Society of Black Engineers Member (2019-present), Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (2019-present), American Society of Mechanical Engineers Member (2019-present)
- Personal Interests: graphic design, photography + videography, traveler, mountain biking, outdoor instructor